# Lilian Okeke

Nigeria | +2348100181416 | Email: lilianokeke.ca@gmail.com | Portfolio: lilydesigned.me

### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

As a Frontend Developer, I specialize in creating immersive user experiences with technologies like React.js, Vue.js, and Flutter. With two years of experience, I've delivered products to clients globally, from startups to corporations. Skilled in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and TypeScript, I focus on blending aesthetics and functionality. Eager to adapt to new technologies, I strive to create digital products that are intuitive and visually captivating.

#### **KEY COMPETENCIES**

Responsive Design
Proficiency in Core Technologies
Framework and Library Expertise

Version Control/Git
Performance Optimization
Cross-browser Compatibility

API Integration
Testing/Debugging
Understanding UX/UI Principles

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Supreme Marketing Limited Lead Frontend Engineer (Full-time)**

Remote, Malta July 2022 - Sept 2023

- Led an Agile team of front-end developers.
- Conducting code reviews, providing technical guidance, and ensuring adherence to coding standards.
- Optimizing website and web application performance to enhance user experience.
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility and followed SEO best practices for all websites.

# Funconnect Frontend Developer (Contract)

Remote, Nigeria Jan 2023 - Present

- Designed, developed, and tested the user interfaces for the Fun Connect Landing Pages, Admin Dashboard, and Users Dashboard web applications.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to define and implement new features and functionality.
- Ensured the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs and optimized website and app performance.

# **BuildingBloques**

## **Product Manager and Frontend Developer**

Remote, United States March 2023 - Aug 2023

- Secured and closed an international contract to develop a mobile and web application for a client in the US.
- Oversaw the design of the mobile and web application as a Product Manager.
- Conducted interviews to recruit a skilled team of mobile, web, and backend developers.
- Managed and coordinated the development process, ensuring timely delivery and adherence to the client's specifications and budget.

### **Education**

#### **ALT SCHOOL AFRICA**

Graduate Diploma in Software Engineering March 2022 - June 2023

#### NNAMDI AZIKIWE UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Education (Honours) Nov 2017 - Dec 2021

# **Technical Skills**

### **TECHNICAL LANGUAGES**

- React.js
- Vue.js
- Flutter
- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Git/GitHub
- npm/Yarn
- AJAX/Fetch

# Reference

Available on request